ANDREW CLARKER

Senior Full Stack Engineer

@ andrewclarker078@gmail.com Plorida

EXPERIENCE

Senior Full Stack Engineer

Katalyst Technologies Inc

09/2020 - Present

Evanston, Illinois, United States

- Led a team of 5 full stack engineers and 3 UX/UI designers, overseeing project planning, execution, and delivery for web and mobile applications
- Managed team performance and development, conducting regular one-on-one meetings and performance reviews, resulting in increased productivity and employee satisfaction
- Improved tools to boost user interaction and deliver design versatility with product managers and increased product performance by 30%
- Collaborated with back-end developers to ensure seamless integration of CMS platforms and front-end designs

Front-end Engineer

Breathing.ai

06/2018 - 06/2020

New York, United States

- Took the lead on creating a visually pleasing and performant website using Gatsby to market and showcase the breathing.ai Chrome extension
- Implemented additional functionality to the Chrome extension using React and JavaScript to provide users with healthier screen time
- Developed and built custom components, implemented RxJS for state management, integrating with APIs
- Optimized website performance, Search Engine Optimization, and implemented the functionality to add blog posts to the website using the Contentful CMS
- Enhanced website user accessibility to a broader audience by incorporating Spanish Localization using i18next
- Coordinated with the UI/UX team using Figma to drive the development and communication of clear design guidelines, patterns, and assets

Front-end Developer

06/2017 - 06/2018

Giovvani

- Worked as a lead UI/UX developer for the Shopify project and collaborated with the product owner, marketing team, and designer to clarify requirements
- Developed company website with Figma design with liquid on online & offline Editor
- · Optimized website performance, and Shopify SEO
- · Built a custom Shopify App interacting with third party APIs such as Klaviyo

SKILLS

Amazon Web Services \cdot Android \cdot AngularJS \cdot API \cdot CMS \cdot CSS \cdot ECommerce \cdot

Figma · Front-end · Git · Html · Html5 · Javascript · Next.js · Node.js · React Native ·

ReactJS · Redux · NextJS · Typescript · Redux.js



SUMMARY

I have over a decade of experience in web and mobile application development, with a strong focus on front-end engineering. As a Senior Full Stack Engineer at Katalyst Technologies, I led a team of 5 engineers and 3 designers, ensuring successful project delivery and enhancing product performance by 30%. Previously, at Breathing ai and Giovvani, I specialized in creating visually appealing websites and implementing functionalities using technologies like React, JavaScript, and CMS platforms. My skill set includes expertise in ReactJS, Next.js, Redux, and AWS, enabling me to optimize performance and user experience effectively.

LANGUAGES

English Proficient ••••

Spanish Advanced ••••

EDUCATION

Bachelor's degree -Information Technology, System Development

Saint Mary's University

02/2014 - 03/2017 San Antonio, Texas, United States

- · San Antonio
- United States
- Bachelor's degree -Information Technology, System Development
- Texas State University